# **Dawit Tewelde**

# Research Assistant - Carnegie Mellon University Cy lab

Oakland, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Dawit-Tewelde/62b2490e4d29ecf1

Over four years' experience performing general software development and data management works, where an In-depth Knowledge in providing strategic guidance regarding Information technology and infrastructural enhancements to clients and organizations with good personal relations and interpersonal skill

Professional Skills Practical and theoretical skills in Software and Web Development

Programming Languages: C++, Python, Matlab, R, Opengl, cudac Software:Latex, Photoshop, 3Ds max, Microsoft office, After Effects.

Operating System: Windows, Linux Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Research Assistant**

Carnegie Mellon University Cy lab - January 2017 to Present

time

- Programing and system implementation of intelligent video analytics system
- · Segmentation and Classification
- Object detection
- Using Opency with C++

## Computer vision Intern

Lab Hubert Curien France - 2016 to July 2016

- Aug -20-2016
- Research and development of new algorithms and mathematical modules for 3D reconstruction using RTI(Reflectance Transform Imaging ) technique.
- Proposing mathematical module for Colour correction of a glossy surfaces of RTI Images

#### **IT Consultant**

Addis Ababa, ET - February 2014 to February 2015

Worked as General IT consultant, carrying out ad-hoc tasks as requested by the college Manager. Had a specific brief to ensure the websites and software's build for the college precisely matched their requirements, network administration and IT services

- Wrote internal and external design specifications.
- Performed maintenance and updates to existing client web based system.
- Involved in user requirements analysis
- · Carried out software data modelling

Participated in teaching computer science courses

## **Programmer - Lia Net**

Software Development Company - Asmara, ER - September 2011 to February 2013

Managed a range of projects, designing appealing web based applications and software interacting on a daily basis with interface designers, back end developers and marketers

- Developing and maintaining the front and back end functionality of software application
- •Developing and maintaining the front and back end functionality of software application
- •Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Designing prototypes for database and software
- •Designing database, Implementing the database and interfaces for websites
- •Writing source code compliant c# & Java
- •Simultaneously managing several databases and reporting tools
- •Using PHP as a server side programming language for web based application
- Developing websites that have a consistent feel and look throughout all web properties
- Providing technical support to end-users
- •Identifying and correcting software deficiencies
- •Integrating and handling financial issues like payroll, benefits, and employees

Teacher - Secondary School, Mai Nefhi (Asmara), Eritrea May

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BSc** in analysis and Design

Eritrean Institute of Technology - Asmara, ER September 2006 to July 2011

## **SKILLS**

Excellent communication skills (Less than 1 year), problem solving (4 years)

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Communication Skills

- Excellent problem solving skills
- Excellent communication skills
- Excellent Inter personal skills and great team work